<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"> <id>/</id><title>Programming With Wolfgang</title><subtitle>A tech blog focusing on DevOps, Cloud, Azure, Kubernetes and Software Architecture.</subtitle> <updated>2022-06-06T16:05:32+02:00</updated> <author> <name>Wolfgang Ofner</name> <uri>/</uri> </author><link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="/feed.xml"/><link rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en" href="/"/> <generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.2">Jekyll</generator> <rights> © 2022 Wolfgang Ofner </rights> <icon>/assets/img/favicons/favicon.ico</icon> <logo>/assets/img/favicons/favicon-96x96.png</logo> <entry><title>Securely connect to an on-premises Kubernetes Cluster with Azure Arc</title><link href="/securely-connect-to-on-premises-kubernetes-with-azure-arc/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Securely connect to an on-premises Kubernetes Cluster with Azure Arc" /><published>2022-06-06T00:00:00+02:00</published> <updated>2022-05-28T18:05:54+02:00</updated> <id>/securely-connect-to-on-premises-kubernetes-with-azure-arc/</id> <content src="/securely-connect-to-on-premises-kubernetes-with-azure-arc/" /> <author> <name>Wolfgang Ofner</name> </author> <category term="Kubernetes" /> <category term="Cloud" /> <summary> In my last post, I installed Azure Arc which allowed me to project my k3s cluster into Azure. The installation was done directly on the Master node of the cluster and developers would also need to connect to the master node to execute any commands on the Kubernetes cluster. Today, I want to show you how to give developers access using RBAC (Role-based access control) and let them connect to th... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>Install Azure Arc on an On-premises k3s Cluster</title><link href="/install-azure-arc-on-premises-k3s-cluster/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Install Azure Arc on an On-premises k3s Cluster" /><published>2022-05-30T00:00:00+02:00</published> <updated>2022-05-27T19:02:35+02:00</updated> <id>/install-azure-arc-on-premises-k3s-cluster/</id> <content src="/install-azure-arc-on-premises-k3s-cluster/" /> <author> <name>Wolfgang Ofner</name> </author> <category term="Kubernetes" /> <category term="Cloud" /> <summary> In my last post, I have created an on-premises k3s cluster and introduced the requirements of this project. One of the requirements/restraints of this project is that the k3s cluster sits behind a firewall that blocks all incoming traffic. Today, I will show you how to install Azure Arc which will help to manage the cluster with Azure, even though it is not accessible over the internet. This ... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>I am back</title><link href="/i-am-back/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="I am back" /><published>2022-05-23T00:00:00+02:00</published> <updated>2022-05-23T00:00:00+02:00</updated> <id>/i-am-back/</id> <content src="/i-am-back/" /> <author> <name>Wolfgang Ofner</name> </author> <category term="Miscellaneous" /> <summary> For the first time in two years, I have taken some time away from my blog. This doesn’t mean that I have been lazy though. First, it was nice to take a step back and take care of my (mental) health. and then I talked at a conference in Germany about KEDA. It was nice to travel and especially be at an in-person conference. It’s been quite some time since the last time. I also started to write r... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>Azure Arc Series - Manage an on-premises Kubernetes Cluster with Azure Arc</title><link href="/manage-on-premises-kubernetes-with-azure-arc/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Azure Arc Series - Manage an on-premises Kubernetes Cluster with Azure Arc" /><published>2022-02-21T00:00:00+01:00</published> <updated>2022-05-29T17:19:22+02:00</updated> <id>/manage-on-premises-kubernetes-with-azure-arc/</id> <content src="/manage-on-premises-kubernetes-with-azure-arc/" /> <author> <name>Wolfgang Ofner</name> </author> <category term="Kubernetes" /> <summary> Azure Arc is a great tool to manage your on-premises hardware with Azure. This series will focus on managing a Kubernetes (k3s) cluster and will show how to install Azure Arc, and how to use different Azure services to manage the cluster. Project Requirements and Restrictions The project for this demo has the following requirements and restrictions: Two on-premises Ubuntu 20.04 VMs Inst... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>Install an on-premises k3s Cluster</title><link href="/install-on-premises-k3s-cluster/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Install an on-premises k3s Cluster" /><published>2022-02-14T00:00:00+01:00</published> <updated>2022-05-26T16:27:22+02:00</updated> <id>/install-on-premises-k3s-cluster/</id> <content src="/install-on-premises-k3s-cluster/" /> <author> <name>Wolfgang Ofner</name> </author> <category term="Kubernetes" /> <summary> Using cloud technologies is amazing and makes a developer’s life so much easier. Lately, I have to work with an on-premises Kubernetes cluster and I had to realize how much work it is to do all these things cloud providers offer. That’s the reason why I got into Azure Arc. In my last post, Azure Arc - Getting Started, I explained what Azure Arc is and how it can be used to manage on-premises re... </summary> </entry> </feed>
