<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"> <id>/</id><title>Programming With Wolfgang</title><subtitle>A tech blog focusing on DevOps, Cloud, Azure, Kubernetes and Software Architecture.</subtitle> <updated>2023-11-14T13:50:23+01:00</updated> <author> <name>Wolfgang Ofner</name> <uri>/</uri> </author><link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="/feed.xml"/><link rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en" href="/"/> <generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.2">Jekyll</generator> <rights> © 2023 Wolfgang Ofner </rights> <icon>/assets/img/favicons/favicon.ico</icon> <logo>/assets/img/favicons/favicon-96x96.png</logo> <entry><title>Fixing Broken Unit Test Execution in Dockerfile</title><link href="/fixing-broken-unit-test-execution-in-dockerfile/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Fixing Broken Unit Test Execution in Dockerfile" /><published>2023-11-06T00:00:00+01:00</published> <updated>2023-11-06T00:00:00+01:00</updated> <id>/fixing-broken-unit-test-execution-in-dockerfile/</id> <content src="/fixing-broken-unit-test-execution-in-dockerfile/" /> <author> <name>Wolfgang Ofner</name> </author> <category term="Docker" /> <category term="Programming" /> <summary> In my demos, I frequently feature code snippets from my “Microservice Series - From Zero to Hero” series. Everything was running like a charm during spring, but upon revisiting it in October, I stumbled upon a puzzling scenario - a broken build. Especially since nothing had changed since I ran the pipeline successfully the last time In this post, I will explain how to fix this issue and updat... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>Article - Azure Arc - The Bridge to the Cloud</title><link href="/article-azure-arc-the-bridge-to-the-cloud/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Article - Azure Arc - The Bridge to the Cloud" /><published>2023-10-30T00:00:00+01:00</published> <updated>2023-10-30T00:00:00+01:00</updated> <id>/article-azure-arc-the-bridge-to-the-cloud/</id> <content src="/article-azure-arc-the-bridge-to-the-cloud/" /> <author> <name>Wolfgang Ofner</name> </author> <category term="Article" /> <summary> This fall, I’m delving into a comprehensive four-part series exploring hybrid cloud solutions through Kubernetes and Azure Arc. The inaugural article, titled “Azure Arc - The Gateway to the Cloud” (Azure Arc - Die Brücke zur Cloud), has been recently featured in the renowned German Windows .developer magazine, even making its front page. You can access the full article on the magazine’s website... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>How to Build Docker Images with Podman using an Azure DevOps Agent in Kubernetes</title><link href="/how-to-build-docker-images-with-podman-using-azure-devops-agent-running-in-kubernetes-copy/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How to Build Docker Images with Podman using an Azure DevOps Agent in Kubernetes" /><published>2023-10-02T00:00:00+02:00</published> <updated>2023-10-02T00:00:00+02:00</updated> <id>/how-to-build-docker-images-with-podman-using-azure-devops-agent-running-in-kubernetes-copy/</id> <content src="/how-to-build-docker-images-with-podman-using-azure-devops-agent-running-in-kubernetes-copy/" /> <author> <name>Wolfgang Ofner</name> </author> <category term="Kubernetes" /> <category term="Cloud" /> <summary> In the previous article, “Mastering Azure DevOps Agents in Kubernetes - A Comprehensive Guide”, we explored the utilization of Azure DevOps agents operating within a Kubernetes cluster, which are dynamically scaled using KEDA. By building the agent from a Dockerfile, you can incorporate all the necessary software for your application’s build process. However, due to the agent’s location within ... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>Speaking about scaling managing On-Premises Kubernetes in the Swiss Alps at KCD Texas 2023</title><link href="/speaking-at-kcd-texas/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Speaking about scaling managing On-Premises Kubernetes in the Swiss Alps at KCD Texas 2023" /><published>2023-09-25T00:00:00+02:00</published> <updated>2023-09-25T00:00:00+02:00</updated> <id>/speaking-at-kcd-texas/</id> <content src="/speaking-at-kcd-texas/" /> <author> <name>Wolfgang Ofner</name> </author> <category term="Speaking" /> <summary> I’m thrilled to announce that I will be speaking at KCD Texas in Irving on October 6, 2023! This is my first time speaking in person in the US, and I am excited to see you all there. You can find more details about the event on the official website. The title of my session is “Optimizing On-Premises Kubernetes: Scaling in the Swiss Alps with Azure”. In this session, we’ll embark on a transform... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>Mastering Azure DevOps Agents in Kubernetes - A Comprehensive Guide</title><link href="/mastering-azure-devops-agents-in-kubernetes-guide/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Mastering Azure DevOps Agents in Kubernetes - A Comprehensive Guide" /><published>2023-09-18T00:00:00+02:00</published> <updated>2023-09-18T00:00:00+02:00</updated> <id>/mastering-azure-devops-agents-in-kubernetes-guide/</id> <content src="/mastering-azure-devops-agents-in-kubernetes-guide/" /> <author> <name>Wolfgang Ofner</name> </author> <category term="Kubernetes" /> <category term="Cloud" /> <summary> Kubernetes, when synergized with applications like KEDA (Kubernetes Event-driven Architecture), becomes a powerful tool. KEDA introduces a scaler into your Kubernetes cluster, enabling workload scaling in response to external events. Imagine a scenario where an Azure DevOps job kick-starts, triggering KEDA to activate an Azure DevOps agent. In this post, I watnt to show you how to deploy an Az... </summary> </entry> </feed>
