<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"> <id>/</id><title>Programming With Wolfgang</title><subtitle>A tech blog focusing on DevOps, Cloud, Azure, Kubernetes and Software Architecture.</subtitle> <updated>2023-08-26T16:19:38+02:00</updated> <author> <name>Wolfgang Ofner</name> <uri>/</uri> </author><link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="/feed.xml"/><link rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en" href="/"/> <generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.2">Jekyll</generator> <rights> © 2023 Wolfgang Ofner </rights> <icon>/assets/img/favicons/favicon.ico</icon> <logo>/assets/img/favicons/favicon-96x96.png</logo> <entry><title>Deploy Helm charts from helm repo</title><link href="/HelmRepo/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Deploy Helm charts from helm repo" /><published>2023-08-24T00:00:00+02:00</published> <updated>2023-08-24T00:00:00+02:00</updated> <id>/HelmRepo/</id> <content src="/HelmRepo/" /> <author> <name>Wolfgang Ofner</name> </author> <category term="Kubernetes" /> <category term="Cloud" /> <summary> Combining Azure Arc with the Flux GitOps extension is a great way to deploy your infrastructure and applications to Kubernetes. In my last post, I showed you how to install the Flux extension and how to configure the deployment using Kustomize and YAML files. Today, I want to show you how to deploy Helm charts using Azure Arc and the Flux GitOps extension. This post is part of “Azure Arc Seri... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>Speaking about scaling Workloads and Azure DevOps Agents running in Kubernetes with KEDA at the Azure User Group Sweden</title><link href="/speaking-at-azure-user-group-sweden/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Speaking about scaling Workloads and Azure DevOps Agents running in Kubernetes with KEDA at the Azure User Group Sweden" /><published>2023-08-21T00:00:00+02:00</published> <updated>2023-08-21T00:00:00+02:00</updated> <id>/speaking-at-azure-user-group-sweden/</id> <content src="/speaking-at-azure-user-group-sweden/" /> <author> <name>Wolfgang Ofner</name> </author> <category term="Speaking" /> <summary> I’m excited to be speaking at the next Azure User Group Sweden meetup. My session, titled “Level Up your Kubernetes Scaling with KEDA”, will be held online on August 26, 2023. In my session, we will discuss the importance of handling varying loads in service-oriented applications and the challenges modern applications face. We will explore how Kubernetes offers a way to vary the number of appl... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>Configuring DNS still sucks in 2023 (featuring Azure Static Web App)</title><link href="/configuring-dns-sucks-in-2023-azure-static-web-app/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Configuring DNS still sucks in 2023 (featuring Azure Static Web App)" /><published>2023-08-15T00:00:00+02:00</published> <updated>2023-08-15T00:00:00+02:00</updated> <id>/configuring-dns-sucks-in-2023-azure-static-web-app/</id> <content src="/configuring-dns-sucks-in-2023-azure-static-web-app/" /> <author> <name>Wolfgang Ofner</name> </author> <summary> Last week, I created a new Office 365 organization since I moved from Australia to Canada, and creating a new one is the only way to move countries. Due to having a new organization, I also had to move my domain and update my DNS configuration for my email server and website which is hosted as an Azure Static Web App. This short post will only be a rant about DNS configurations sucking and wil... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>Troubleshooting Stuck Kubernetes Namespaces</title><link href="/troubleshooting-stuck-kubernetes-namespaces/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Troubleshooting Stuck Kubernetes Namespaces" /><published>2023-07-17T00:00:00+02:00</published> <updated>2023-07-17T00:00:00+02:00</updated> <id>/troubleshooting-stuck-kubernetes-namespaces/</id> <content src="/troubleshooting-stuck-kubernetes-namespaces/" /> <author> <name>Wolfgang Ofner</name> </author> <category term="Kubernetes" /> <category term="Cloud" /> <summary> Recently, I have been exploring various Azure Arc extensions, and during the process of installing and uninstalling them, I encountered a scenario where a namespace became stuck while attempting to delete it. Resolving this issue presents two potential solutions: either deleting the entire cluster and starting afresh or addressing the problem within the namespace’s manifest. Since deleting the... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>Speaking about scaling Workloads and Azure DevOps Agents running in Kubernetes with KEDA at the Advanced Kubernetes Day</title><link href="/Scaling-Workloads-and-Azure-DevOps-Agents-with-KEDA-at-Advanced-Kubernetes-Day/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Speaking about scaling Workloads and Azure DevOps Agents running in Kubernetes with KEDA at the Advanced Kubernetes Day" /><published>2023-07-10T00:00:00+02:00</published> <updated>2023-07-10T00:00:00+02:00</updated> <id>/Scaling-Workloads-and-Azure-DevOps-Agents-with-KEDA-at-Advanced-Kubernetes-Day/</id> <content src="/Scaling-Workloads-and-Azure-DevOps-Agents-with-KEDA-at-Advanced-Kubernetes-Day/" /> <author> <name>Wolfgang Ofner</name> </author> <category term="Kubernetes" /> <category term="Cloud" /> <summary> I’m excited to announce that I will be speaking at the upcoming “Advanced Kubernetes Day” event on July 11, 2023. Join me online as I present a session titled: “Scaling to Success: Leveraging KEDA and Kubernetes for Optimal Performance.” During our time together, we will explore the practical application of KEDA (Kubernetes-based Event-Driven Autoscaling) to efficiently scale Azure DevOps pipe... </summary> </entry> </feed>
