<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"> <id>/</id><title>Programming With Wolfgang</title><subtitle>A tech blog focusing on DevOps, Cloud, Azure, Kubernetes and Software Architecture.</subtitle> <updated>2022-08-17T14:22:54+02:00</updated> <author> <name>Wolfgang Ofner</name> <uri>/</uri> </author><link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="/feed.xml"/><link rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en" href="/"/> <generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.2">Jekyll</generator> <rights> © 2022 Wolfgang Ofner </rights> <icon>/assets/img/favicons/favicon.ico</icon> <logo>/assets/img/favicons/favicon-96x96.png</logo> <entry><title>Create a VPC Connection between Azure and Timescale</title><link href="/create-vpc-connection-between-azure-and-timescale/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Create a VPC Connection between Azure and Timescale" /><published>2022-08-15T00:00:00+02:00</published> <updated>2022-08-15T00:00:00+02:00</updated> <id>/create-vpc-connection-between-azure-and-timescale/</id> <content src="/create-vpc-connection-between-azure-and-timescale/" /> <author> <name>Wolfgang Ofner</name> </author> <category term="Cloud" /> <summary> This week, I was helping a customer of mine to migrate from an on-prem database to a cloud-hosted TimescaleDB. Since the customer is using Azure, they wanted to host their new TimescaleDB in Azure. Timescale offers to host the database on Azure and also allows a private connection via VPC (virtual private cloud) peering. This allows customers to peer a VNet with the VNet of Timescale and there... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>Introducing GitOps</title><link href="/introducing-gitops/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Introducing GitOps" /><published>2022-08-08T00:00:00+02:00</published> <updated>2022-08-08T00:00:00+02:00</updated> <id>/introducing-gitops/</id> <content src="/introducing-gitops/" /> <author> <name>Wolfgang Ofner</name> </author> <category term="Kubernetes" /> <category term="DevOps" /> <summary> GitOps is a way to manage infrastructure as code (IaC) which gains more and more traction lately. Today, I want to give you an introduction to GitOps, talk about the good and bad, and also introduce some GitOps tools you can use to get started. This post is part of “Azure Arc Series - Manage an on-premises Kubernetes Cluster with Azure Arc”. What is GitOps? Infrastructure as code is nothing... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>Use the TokenRequest API to create Tokens in Kubernetes 1.24</title><link href="/use-the-tokenrequest-api-to-create-tokens-in-kubernetes/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Use the TokenRequest API to create Tokens in Kubernetes 1.24" /><published>2022-08-01T00:00:00+02:00</published> <updated>2022-08-01T00:00:00+02:00</updated> <id>/use-the-tokenrequest-api-to-create-tokens-in-kubernetes/</id> <content src="/use-the-tokenrequest-api-to-create-tokens-in-kubernetes/" /> <author> <name>Wolfgang Ofner</name> </author> <category term="Kubernetes" /> <category term="Cloud" /> <summary> In one of my former posts, Securely connect to an on-premises Kubernetes Cluster with Azure Arc, I showed you how to securely connect to an on-premise Kubernetes cluster using Azure Arc. To achieve that, I have create a user and then retrieved the token of the user. This method has changed a bit from Kubernetes version 1.24 on and in this post, I will show you how to get this token if you are ... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>Programming With Wolfgang is now on Youtube</title><link href="/programming-with-wolfgang-youtube-channel/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Programming With Wolfgang is now on Youtube" /><published>2022-07-25T00:00:00+02:00</published> <updated>2022-07-25T00:00:00+02:00</updated> <id>/programming-with-wolfgang-youtube-channel/</id> <content src="/programming-with-wolfgang-youtube-channel/" /> <author> <name>Wolfgang Ofner</name> </author> <category term="Youtube" /> <summary> As the title already mentions, I have created a Youtube channel and uploaded my first video explaining how to install Azure Arc to manage an on-premise Kubernetes cluster. I am not sure yet where this channel will go but for now, I will try to bring you the same educational content as I do on my blog. If you want to share or introduce a topic, feel free to text me. I am happy to host guests a... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>Speaking about KEDA at the Kubernetes Community Days 2022 in Berlin</title><link href="/speaking-about-keda-at-the-kcd-berlin-2022/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Speaking about KEDA at the Kubernetes Community Days 2022 in Berlin" /><published>2022-06-20T00:00:00+02:00</published> <updated>2022-06-20T00:00:00+02:00</updated> <id>/speaking-about-keda-at-the-kcd-berlin-2022/</id> <content src="/speaking-about-keda-at-the-kcd-berlin-2022/" /> <author> <name>Wolfgang Ofner</name> </author> <category term="Miscellaneous" /> <summary> I am excited to announce that I will be speaking at the Kubernetes Community Days 2022 in Berlin. My session will be on Wednesday, July 29 live on stage. If you are in Berlin, check out my talk and say hi. The abstract for my session is as follows: Level Up your Kubernetes Scaling with KEDA Whether it is a normal workday or Black Friday, service-oriented applications must be able to handle v... </summary> </entry> </feed>
