<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"> <id>/</id><title>Programming With Wolfgang</title><subtitle>A tech blog focusing on DevOps, Cloud, Azure, Kubernetes and Software Architecture.</subtitle> <updated>2022-05-05T10:57:04+02:00</updated> <author> <name>Wolfgang Ofner</name> <uri>/</uri> </author><link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="/feed.xml"/><link rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en" href="/"/> <generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.2">Jekyll</generator> <rights> © 2022 Wolfgang Ofner </rights> <icon>/assets/img/favicons/favicon.ico</icon> <logo>/assets/img/favicons/favicon-96x96.png</logo> <entry><title>Azure Arc Series - Manage an on-premises Kubernetes Cluster with Azure Arc</title><link href="/manage-on-premises-kubernetes-with-azure-arc/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Azure Arc Series - Manage an on-premises Kubernetes Cluster with Azure Arc" /><published>2022-02-21T00:00:00+01:00</published> <updated>2022-02-21T00:00:00+01:00</updated> <id>/manage-on-premises-kubernetes-with-azure-arc/</id> <content src="/manage-on-premises-kubernetes-with-azure-arc/" /> <author> <name>Wolfgang Ofner</name> </author> <category term="Kubernetes" /> <summary> Azure Arc is a great tool to manage your on-premises hardware with Azure. This series will focus on managing a Kubernetes (k3s) cluster and will show how to install Azure Arc, and how to use different Azure services to manage the cluster. Project Requirements and Restrictions The project for this demo has the following requirements and restrictions: Two on-premises Ubuntu 20.04 VMs Inst... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>Install an on-premises k3s Cluster</title><link href="/install-on-premises-k3s-cluster/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Install an on-premises k3s Cluster" /><published>2022-02-14T00:00:00+01:00</published> <updated>2022-02-14T00:00:00+01:00</updated> <id>/install-on-premises-k3s-cluster/</id> <content src="/install-on-premises-k3s-cluster/" /> <author> <name>Wolfgang Ofner</name> </author> <category term="Kubernetes" /> <summary> Using cloud technologies is amazing and makes a developer’s life so much easier. Lately, I have to work with an on-premises Kubernetes cluster and I had to realize how much work it is to do all these things cloud providers offer. That’s the reason why I got into Azure Arc. In my last post, Azure Arc - Getting Started, I explained what Azure Arc is and how it can be used to manage on-premises re... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>Speaking about KEDA at the BASTA! Conference in Frankfurt</title><link href="/speaking-about-keda-at-the-basta-conference/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Speaking about KEDA at the BASTA! Conference in Frankfurt" /><published>2022-02-07T00:00:00+01:00</published> <updated>2022-02-16T18:02:15+01:00</updated> <id>/speaking-about-keda-at-the-basta-conference/</id> <content src="/speaking-about-keda-at-the-basta-conference/" /> <author> <name>Wolfgang Ofner</name> </author> <category term="Miscellaneous" /> <summary> There is light at the end of the tunnel with the pandemic and therefore in person conferences and international travel is coming back. I am excited to travel to Germany and speak at the BASTA! conference in Frankfurt about KEDA. You can join the session in-person, or remote to learn more about KEDA. If you can’t make it to the conference but still want to learn more about KEDA, see KEDA - Kube... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>Introducing Kubernetes Services</title><link href="/introducing-kubernetes-services/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Introducing Kubernetes Services" /><published>2022-01-31T00:00:00+01:00</published> <updated>2022-02-27T16:14:09+01:00</updated> <id>/introducing-kubernetes-services/</id> <content src="/introducing-kubernetes-services/" /> <author> <name>Wolfgang Ofner</name> </author> <category term="Kubernetes" /> <summary> Pods can be deleted and recreated at any time, making them a so-called nonpermanent resource in Kubernetes. Therefore, the IP address of a pod will likely change regularly. This behavior will cause problems when you have a resource, for example, a DNS record, pointing to your application. It will be impossible to route to the application since the IP address of the pods will always change. Thi... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>Use .NET Secrets in a Console Application</title><link href="/use-net-secrets-in-console-application/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Use .NET Secrets in a Console Application" /><published>2022-01-24T00:00:00+01:00</published> <updated>2022-01-24T00:00:00+01:00</updated> <id>/use-net-secrets-in-console-application/</id> <content src="/use-net-secrets-in-console-application/" /> <author> <name>Wolfgang Ofner</name> </author> <category term="Programming" /> <summary> .NET Core made it easy to configure your application. Currently, I am working on a .NET 6 console application and this showed me that especially ASP.NET MVC makes it easy to set up middleware such as dependency injection. When using a console application, it is not hard but it requires a bit more work than the web application. In this post, I would like to show you how to use .NET secrets in y... </summary> </entry> </feed>
